Finding Aid for Lana Pollack Papers 1979-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Lana Pollack Papers
1979-2010
Pollack, Lana, 1942-
Lana Pollack served as state senator for Michigan's Eighteenth District from 1982 to 1994. The collection documents her legislative and political activities and include subject files, campaign materials, and audio-visual materials.
9570 Aa 2
19 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Lana Pollack (donor 8341 ) in March 1995. Periodic additions have been received.
The collection is open for research.
Lana Pollack served as state senator for Michigan's Eighteenth District from 1982 to 1994. A liberal Democrat, Pollack earned a reputation as an outspoken and hardworking legislator.
Pollack was born near Ludington, Michigan on October 11, 1942; her parents ran a grocery and butcher shop. She grew up in Ludington and attended the University of Michigan, where she earned a Bachelor of Arts in political science in 1965, and a Master of Arts in Education in 1970. While she was working on her degrees, she married geology professor Henry Pollack and had two children. It was not until the late 1960s that Pollack became active in politics as a volunteer worker for the Ann Arbor Democratic Party. During this period of her life, Pollack's first priority was her family rather than politics. She accompanied her husband on sabbaticals in Africa and England, and travelled widely during the 1970s.
Another high priority for Pollack during the 1970s was to work as a teacher, but she was unable to find a permanent position; after years of substitute teaching and working on other candidates' campaigns, she successfully ran for the Ann Arbor Board of Education in 1979. The quality of her work as a Board member led to a landslide victory when she ran for state Senate in 1982. This was especially impressive since Michigan's Senate had been an all-male institution for twenty-two years prior to Pollack's election.
Major issues which came to be associated with Pollack were family and women's rights concerns, anti-pollution legislation, support for the arts, and tax equity. She organized a bi-partisan statewide coalition to discourage teenage pregnancy called the Campaign to Promote Responsibility, as well as the Gun Violence Coalition, which was an education and pro-gun control effort.
In 1988 Pollack ran for Congress against Republican incumbent Carl Pursell. She lost, but proved to be a strong campaigner and prodigious fundraiser. This gave her the confidence to run for a vacant United States Senate seat in 1994; in a tough primary, she finished second to Congressman Bob Carr. In spite of a successful fundraising effort and endorsements by prominent Democrats and labor leaders, Pollack could not match Carr's financial backing. Since she had given up her senate seat to run federally, Pollack moved on to a new career in 1995 when she helped found Michigan Monthly magazine.
In 1998 Pollack helped found Save Our Land, Save Our Future (SOLSOF) to support Washtenaw County’s Purchase of Development Rights (PDR) proposal, which was intended to protect farmland and open space in Washtenaw County. She also served as chair of the campaign committee. Opposition to the proposal was led by Washtenaw Citizens for Responsible Growth. Following the rejection of the proposal she returned to her work with the Michigan Environmental Council. After she retired from his position in 2008, she continued her involvement with environmental issues in Michigan by leading protests related to the conversion of Jean Klock Park in Benton Harbor. She also served on the board of the Michigan Natural Resources Trust Fund.
The Lana Pollack collection documents diverse aspects of Pollack's legislative and political activities. The papers have been divided into seven series: Ann Arbor Board of Education; Michigan Senate; Campaigns; Photographs; Audiotapes; Videotapes; and Other Projects.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.). Board of Education.; Carr, Bob, 1943-; Elections--Michigan--1982.; Elections--Michigan--1986.; Elections--Michigan--1988.; Elections--Michigan--1994.; Environmental protection--Michigan.; Fund raising--Michigan.; Gun control--Michigan.; Jews--Michigan--Politics and government.; Jean Klock Park (Benton Harbor, Mich.); Legislators--Michigan.; Michigan. Legislature. Senate.; Michigan Natural Resources Trust Fund.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-; Michigan--Politics and government--1981-1990.; Michigan--Politics and government--1991-2000.; Pollack, Lana, 1942-; Pollution--Law and legislation--Michigan.; Teenage pregnancy--Michigan.; Women in politics--Michigan.; Women legislators--Michigan.; Women's rights--Michigan.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Blanchard, James J., 1942-; Ferraro, Geraldine.; Legislative bodies.; Legislators--Michigan.; Michigan. Legislature. Senate.; Pollack, Lana, 1942-; Schembechler, Bo.
Subjects - Sound Recordings
Pollack, Lana, 1942-; Elections--Michigan--1988.; Michigan--Politics and government--1981-1990.; Michigan--Politics and government--1991-2000.; Women's rights--Michigan.
Genre/Form:
Photographs.; Sound recordings.; Videotapes.
- Ann Arbor Board Of Education
  Ann Arbor Board Of Education (.25 linear ft.; 1979-1982) consists of correspondence, notes and clippings from Pollack's first elective office. Of particular interest are notes and background materials relating to the controversy over the teaching of "Black English" in Ann Arbor public schools.
  - Clippings, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Litigation
    - Background Materials, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
    - Black English, 1979-1981; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Michigan Out of Formula District Association, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Notes and Correspondence, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Superintendent Hiring, 1981 (Box 1)
- Michigan Senate
  Michigan Senate (7.75 linear ft.; 1982-1994) includes correspondence, speeches, memoranda, clippings and schedules which document the many issues and responsibilities Pollack dealt with during her years as a state senator.
  The series is divided into several subseries: Constituent Case Files; Fundraising; Speech Files; Legislation and Amendments Introduced by LP; Organization Files; Subject Files; Correspondence; and Office Administration.
  - Constituent Case Files [samples], 1983-1990; 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Fundraising, 1988-1992
    - Contributions, 1988-1993 (Box 1)
    - Events
      - Ark Event (Box 1)
      - Ann Arbor (Box 1)
      - Detroit/Vincent (Box 1)
      - Flint (Box 1)
      - Huntington Woods (Box 1)
      - Lansing (Box 1)
      - Ludington (Box 1)
      - Marquette (Box 1)
      - Mount Pleasant (Box 1)
    - EMILY's List, 1988-1992; 4 folders (Box 1)
    - "Our Choice,", 1990-1992; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Speech Files
    - Ann Arbor-2000 The Future of the Ann Arbor Area, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Ann Arbor Chamber Speech, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Arts, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Black-Jewish Alliance, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Brown Chapel Banquet Speech, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Capital Area Women's Network, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Center for Independent Living, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Children at Risk, undated (Box 1)
    - Civil Rights in the Workplace-Handicappers, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Civil Rights Leadership Conference, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Coalition of Labor Union Women, 1987 (Box 1)
    - "Collision of Politics and Religion: A Jewish Politician's Perspective of the Contraception-Abortion Debate,", circa 1989 (Box 2)
    - Community College Association, circa 1985 (Box 2)
    - Court Appointed Special Advocates, 1987 (Box 2)
    - "Debate" on latkes, 1990 (Box 2)
    - Domestic Violence, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Economic Recovery and Economic Development, circa 1989 (Box 2)
    - Excellence in Education-A Legislative Point of View, 1984 (Box 2)
    - Families, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Federal Education Appropriations, circa 1990 (Box 2)
    - Free Speech, circa 1990 (Box 2)
    - Funding for Education, undated (Box 2)
    - Gender Discrimination, undated (Box 2)
    - Graduation Speeches, circa 1989-1993 (Box 2)
    - Health, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Health Policy Forum, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Holocaust Remembrance, 1988; 1993 (Box 2)
    - Huron Valley Occupational Therapists, undated (Box 2)
    - Job Training Speech, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Lesbian/Gay Rights, circa 1991 (Box 2)
    - Maternal and Infant Health Conference, 1992 (Box 2)
    - MEA [Michigan Education Association] Joint Third World and Women's Legislative Forum, 1985 (Box 2)
    - MEA Unity Conference, undated (Box 2)
    - Mental Health, 1985 (Box 2)
    - Multicultural Education, 1994 (Box 2)
    - "A Nation at Risk"-A Legislative Response, 1984 (Box 2)
    - Nurses, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Personnel Association, undated (Box 2)
    - Senior Issues, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Senior Law Day, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Teen Pregnancy, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Third Parties, undated (Box 2)
    - Unemployment Insurance, 1993 (Box 2)
    - University of Michigan
      - Critical Care Medicine Unit, 1983 (Box 2)
      - Faculty Senate, 1990 (Box 2)
      - Flint Debate, undated (Box 2)
      - Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations, 1983 (Box 2)
      - School of Social Work Graduation Speech, 1991 (Box 2)
    - Urban Problems, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Volunteers, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Washtenaw Community College, 1983 (Box 2)
    - "Why I am a Democrat,", undated (Box 2)
    - Women and Leadership, undated (Box 2)
    - Women in Health Care Management, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Women's Day Speech, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Women's Health Issues, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Legislation and amendments introduced by LP
    - 1983-1993, 13 folders (Box 2)
    - Legislation signed into law, 1982-1988 (Box 3)
    - Senate journal, 1983-1993 (Box 3)
    - Voting record, 1983-1987 (Box 3)
  - Organization files
    - Washtenaw County
      - Alliance for the Mentally Ill, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
      - Arbor Hospice, 1992 (Box 3)
      - Child and Family Services of Washtenaw County, Inc., 1990 (Box 3)
      - Child Care Coordinating and Referral Service, 1986-1988 (Box 3)
      - Christmas in, April, 1992 (Box 3)
      - COPE [Center for Occupational and Personalized Education, Inc.]/ O'Brien Center, 1986-1990 (Box 3)
      - Dawn Farm, 1994 (Box 3)
      - Foster Grandparents, 1988-1993 (Box 3)
      - Human Services Board, 1988-1993 (Box 3)
      - SAFE House [Shelter Available for Emergency], 1992 (Box 3)
      - Senior Citizens' Guild, 1986 (Box 3)
      - Senior Site Visits, 1986 (Box 3)
      - Vietnam Veterans, 1987-1990 (Box 3)
      - WARC [Washtenaw Association for Retarded Citizens], 1990-1993 (Box 3)
      - Washtenaw County, 1990-1994 (Box 3)
      - Washtenaw County Mental Health Facilities, 1991 (Box 3)
    - Ann Arbor
      - Ann Arbor Center for Independent Living, 1990-1992 (Box 3)
      - Ann Arbor Community Development Corp., 1992-1993 (Box 3)
      - Ann Arbor Holocaust Remembrance Commission, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
      - Glacier Hills, 1986-1991 (Box 3)
      - Hands-On-Museum, 1988-1992 (Box 3)
      - Housing Bureau for Seniors, 1985-1994 (Box 3)
      - KMS Fusion, Inc., 1990 (Box 3)
      - Michigan Natural Resources Trust Fund for North Main Corridor, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
      - Ozone House, 1990-1993 (Box 3)
      - Perry Nursery School, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
      - Shelter Association of Ann Arbor, 1990-1993 (Box 3)
      - Whitehall Convalescent Homes, 1992 (Box 3)
    - Ypsilanti
      - City of Ypsilanti, 1986-1994 (Box 3)
      - The Corner Health Center, 1984-1993 (Box 3)
      - Foster Care Homes Licensing, 1990-1993 (Box 3)
      - Public Health Screening, 1989-1992 (Box 3)
      - SOS Community Crisis Center, 1989-1994 (Box 3)
    - The University of Michigan
      - Admissions, 1987-8 (Box 4)
      - Affirmative Action, 1987-1993 (Box 4)
      - Campus Police Legislation, 1987-1992 (Box 4)
      - Computer fees, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
      - Computer sales, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
      - Correspondence and Constituent Problems, 1984-1990 (Box 4)
      - Correspondence and Constituent Problems, 1991-1994 (Box 4)
      - Douglas Lake, 1988-1991 (Box 4)
      - Downsizing, 1983 (Box 4)
      - Genetic Screening Program, 1991 (Box 4)
      - Impact of U of M on Washtenaw County, 1990 (Box 4)
      - Nurse Midwives, 1992 (Box 4)
      - Ohio State Game Wager, 1985-1992 (Box 4)
      - Power, Eugene, 1993 (Box 4)
      - Racism Hearing, 1987-1990 (Box 4)
      - Residency Requests, 1984-1993 (Box 4)
      - Schembechler Reception, 1990 (Box 4)
      - State Payment for U of M Fire Protection, 1980 (Box 4)
      - Tenure, 1993 (Box 4)
      - Ufer Quarterback Club, 1992 (Box 4)
      - University of Michigan at Dearborn, 1983-1991 (Box 4)
  - Subject files
    - Arts
      - Ann Arbor Chamber Orchestra, 1988-1990 (Box 4)
      - Ann Arbor Summer Festival, 1990 (Box 4)
      - Ann Arbor Symphony Orchestra, 1991 (Box 4)
      - Artsgrowth-Huron Valley Men's Facility, 1986-1990 (Box 4)
      - Correspondence, 1983-1993 (Box 4)
      - Flute Festival, 1993-1994 (Box 4)
      - Marceau, Marcel, 1986-1987 (Box 4)
      - Michigan Council for the Arts, 1987-1993 (Box 4)
      - NEW Center (McKinley Foundation), 1990-1992 (Box 4)
    - Campaign to Promote Responsibility [CPR]
      - Alpena, 1993-1994 (Box 4)
      - Background, 1993-1994 (Box 4)
      - Brochure, 1993-1994 (Box 4)
      - Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 4)
      - Escanaba, 1993 (Box 4)
      - First Forum, 1993 (Box 4)
      - Flint, 1993 (Box 4)
      - Funding, 1993 (Box 4)
      - Hearing Updates, 1994 (Box 4)
      - Kalamazoo, 1994 (Box 4)
      - Lerner, Dr. Richard, 1992-1993 (Box 4)
      - Oakland County, 1994 (Box 4)
      - Press Conference, 1992 (Box 4)
      - Steering Committee, 1994 (Box 5)
      - Video Marketing and Distribution, 1994 (Box 5)
      - Video Project, 1994 (Box 5)
    - Corporal Punishment
      - Coalition to Abolish Corporal Punishment, 1987 (Box 5)
      - Correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 5)
      - Hyman, Dr. Irwin, 1987 (Box 5)
      - New Contacts, 1983-1988 (Box 5)
      - Public Schools, 1983-1988 (Box 5)
    - Crime and Gun Control
      - Acceptance Letters, 1993 (Box 5)
      - Action Alert, 1994 (Box 5)
      - Coalition on Gun Violence Background Materials, 1993 (Box 5)
      - Correspondence on Gun Violence Coalition, 1994 (Box 5)
      - Data on Women, 1993 (Box 5)
      - Female Prisoners Data, 1994 (Box 5)
      - Glover Consent Decree, 1993 (Box 5)
      - Gun Legislation, 1993-1994 (Box 5)
      - Gun Violence Press Conference, 1993 (Box 5)
      - Harper, Maxine, 1993 (Box 5)
      - Michigan Anti-Violence Coalition, 1993 (Box 5)
      - Prisoner/ Sex Offender Therapy, 1993-1994 (Box 5)
      - WISH [Women Improving Sexual Health], Scott Prison, 1992-1993 (Box 5)
      - Women in Prison, 1992-1993 (Box 5)
    - Environment
      - Environment Legislation
        - Constituent Correspondence, 1990 (Box 5)
        - Press Releases, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
        - Summaries, circa 1990 (Box 5)
        - Testimony, 1985-1990 (Box 5)
      - Environment Package Analysis, 1985-1987 (Box 5)
      - Environmental Enforcement Package, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
      - Environmental Response Act Amendments, 1987-1990 (Box 5)
      - Environmental Task Force, 1984-1986 (Box 5)
      - "Polluters Pay" Bill, 1989-1990 (Box 5)
    - Golf Club Discrimination
      - Clippings, 1991-1992 (Box 5)
      - Clubs with Liquor Licenses, 1991-1992 (Box 5)
      - Correspondence, 1991-1993 (Box 5)
      - PA 70, 1992 (Box 5)
      - SB 165/351, 1991-1993 (Box 5)
    - Jewish Groups and Issues
      - Israel, 1987-1994 (Box 5)
      - Jewish Contacts in Michigan, 1985-1990 (Box 5)
      - Jewish/Palestinian Women Work Group, 1989-1991 (Box 5)
    - Women's Issues
      - Choice, 1986-1990 (Box 6)
      - Convention on the Elimination of Discrimination Against Women [CEDAW], 1994 (Box 6)
      - Domestic Violence Legislation, 1989-1990 (Box 6)
      - Family Planning Legislation, 1987-1990
        - Correspondence, 1989-90 (Box 6)
        - Public Funding for Abortion, Background Documents, 1987 (Box 6)
        - Senate Bill 884, 1990 (Box 6)
      - Health Care Access Protection Act, 1992 (Box 6)
      - Michigan Women's Foundation, 1990-1993 (Box 6)
      - Our Choice, 1991-1992 (Box 6)
      - Pay Equity, 1993 (Box 6)
      - Potty Parity, 1993 (Box 6)
      - Safer Society Resources of Michigan, 1993 (Box 6)
      - Sex Legislation Information, 1994 (Box 6)
      - Sex Offender Legislation, 1993-1994 (Box 6)
      - Women's Leadership Forum, 1989 (Box 6)
      - Health Care Access Protection Act, 1992 (Box 6)
      - Michigan Women's Foundation, 1990-1993 (Box 6)
      - Our Choice, 1991-1992 (Box 6)
      - Pay Equity, 1993 (Box 6)
      - Potty Parity, 1993 (Box 6)
      - Safer Society Resources of Michigan, 1993 (Box 6)
      - Sex Legislation Information, 1994 (Box 6)
      - Sex Offender Legislation, 1993-1994 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous Subject Files
      - Barrier Free Design Issues, 1987-1988 (Box 6)
      - Bolcom/Morris Fundraiser for Homeless Veterans, 1991-1992 (Box 6)
      - Capitol Restoration, 1988-1991 (Box 6)
      - Cigarette Tax Letters, 1992 (Box 6)
      - DeBoer Adoption/ Custody Case, 1993 (Box 6)
      - Engler Cuts, 1991-1992 (Box 6)
      - Envotech/ Augusta Development, 1992 (Box 6)
      - Gelman Sciences, 1992 (Box 6)
      - Health Care Access Protection Act, 1990 (Box 6)
      - Incinerator Ash, 1989 (Box 6)
      - Insurance: Anti-Trust Exemption and Rates, 1989-1990 (Box 6)
      - Legislative Service Bureau, 1982-1988 (Box 6)
      - Math Awareness Week, 1987 (Box 6)
      - Maxey/ Whitmore Lake Public Schools, 1991 (Box 6)
      - Michigan Library Board, 1993-1994 (Box 6)
      - Napier Dump, 1990 (Box 6)
      - Off-Road Vehicles, 1990 (Box 6)
      - Organ Transplantation, 1987 (Box 6)
      - Parental Consent Bill, 1989 (Box 6)
      - Pay Raise Issue, 1983-1989 (Box 6)
      - Pesticides, 1991-1992 (Box 6)
      - Plain Language, 1989 (Box 6)
      - Pledge and Flag, 1982-1988 (Box 6)
      - Pornography, 1988-1990 (Box 6)
      - Portage Lake Sewer Project, 1990 (Box 6)
      - Prefunding, 1992 (Box 6)
      - Property Tax Reform, 1990 (Box 6)
      - Radar Detectors, 1987 (Box 6)
      - Saline Area Schools, 1994 (Box 6)
      - School Finance Reform, 1988-1990 (Box 6)
      - Senior Citizen's City, 1993 (Box 6)
      - Sesquicentennial, 1984-1986 (Box 7)
      - Unemployment Compensation for Non-Instructional School Staff, 1992 (Box 7)
      - Universal Health Care Legislation, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
      - Visiting Committee, School of Education Alumni, 1990 (Box 7)
      - Ypsilanti Schools, 1990 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence
    - Congratulations Letters, 1982 (Box 7)
    - Constituent Letters [sample], 1989-1993; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - "Crazy Mail,", 1987-1994 (Box 7)
    - Detroit News"Worst" List, 1992 (Box 7)
    - Dinello/ Welborn, 1993 (Box 7)
    - Gelman, Charles, 1989-1991 (Box 7)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1983-1994 (Box 7)
  - Office Administration
    - Archives/ Senate Office, 1983-1984 (Box 7)
    - Intra-Office Correspondence, 1983-1986 (Box 7)
    - Office Organization, 1982-1984 (Box 7)
    - Office Personnel, 1983-1991 (Box 7)
    - Press clippings binder, 1982-1993 (Box 8)
    - Press Releases and Newsletters, 1983-1994; 13 folders (Box 8)
    - Schedules, 1982-1989; 1992; 4 folders (Box 8)
- Campaigns
  Campaigns (7.5 linear ft.; 1982-2000) are arranged by campaign, in chronological order, and include correspondence, memoranda, polls, and financial records. The series documents the many facets of political campaigning, particularly organization, strategy, staffing and fundraising. Campaign literature and extensive files about Pollack's opponents are included in the series, as well as polls of prospective voters which were commissioned for the 1988 and 1994 campaigns. Comprehensive opposition research completed on Pollack, including a substantial biography, is included with the files relating to her 1994 Senate campaign. This series also includes files related to Pollack’s role in Save Our Land, Save Our Future and the 1988 campaign surrounding the Washtenaw County Purchase of Development Rights proposal.
  - State Senate, 1982
    - Campaign
      - Issues, 1982 (Box 9)
      - Literature, 1982 (Box 9)
      - Scrapbook, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Canvassing, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Election Committee, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Endorsements Sought and Received, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Get Out The Vote, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Literature Drops, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Newspaper Adverts, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Newspaper Questionnaires, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Opponent File, Roy Smith, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Press Releases, 1982 (Box 9)
  - State Senate, 1986
    - Advertising, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Biographical Information, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Budget, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Campaign
      - Finance Committee, 1986 (Box 9)
      - General Events Committee, 1986 (Box 9)
      - Literature, 1986 (Box 9)
      - Meeting Minutes, 1986 (Box 9)
      - Strategy Documents, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 9)
    - District Fundraisers, 1984-1986 (Box 9)
    - House Parties and Coffees, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Opponent File (Dale J. Apley, Jr.), 1986 (Box 9)
    - Polling, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Press Releases, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Primary Financing, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Questionnaires, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Receipt of Nominating Position Filed, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Schedules, 1986 (Box 9)
    - "Senatorial Club" Letter, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Volunteers, 1986 (Box 9)
  - United States Congress, 1988
    - Analysis Group Polls for Michigan's 2nd Congressional District, 1986-1988; 8 folders (Box 9)
    - Analysis Group Polls for Michigan's 2nd Congressional District, 1988; 4 folders (Box 10)
    - Ann Arbor, 1988 (Box 10)
    - Bates and Associates, 1987-1988 (Box 10)
    - Banking, 1987-1988 (Box 10)
    - Budgeting, 1988 (Box 10)
    - Campaign
      - Advice, 1988 (Box 10)
      - Literature, 1988 (Box 10)
      - Newsletters, 1988 (Box 10)
      - Planning
        - General, 1987-1988; 2 folders (Box 10)
        - Meetings, 1987-1988 (Box 10)
      - Staffing, 1988 (Box 10)
    - Canvassing Materials, 1988 (Box 10)
    - Contacts, 1987-1988 (Box 10)
    - Contributions Reports, 1988 (Box 10)
    - Debates, 1988 (Box 10)
    - Democratic Congressional Campaign Committee (DCCC), 1988 (Box 10)
    - Democratic National Convention Trip, 1988 (Box 10)
    - Democratic Primary, 1988 (Box 10)
    - Endorsements, 1988; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Federal Election Commission, 1988 (Box 10)
    - Field Plans, 1988 (Box 10)
    - Finance Committee, 1988 (Box 10)
    - Focus Groups, 1988 (Box 10)
    - Fundraising
      - General, 1988 (Box 10)
      - How-To, 1988 (Box 10)
      - Letters, 1987-1988 (Box 10)
      - Reports, 1988 (Box 10)
    - Fundraisers
      - Breakfast, 12/11/1987 (Box 10)
      - California Trip, 1987-1988
        - CAWP Forum, 1987 (Box 10)
        - Miscellaneous, 1987-8 (Box 10)
        - Thank You notes, 1987 (Box 10)
      - California Trip, 1988 (Box 10)
      - Invitations, 1988 (Box 10)
      - McIntosh and Gazda Party, 1988 (Box 10)
      - New York Party, 1988 (Box 10)
      - Peace and Justice Fundraiser, 1988 (Box 10)
      - Planning, 1988 (Box 10)
      - Rezmierski Reception, 1988 (Box 10)
    - Hillsdale, 1988 (Box 10)
    - Information Packet, Pre-Campaign, 1985-1987 (Box 10)
    - Issue Files
      - AFL-CIO, 1988 (Box 10)
      - Central America, 1988 (Box 10)
      - Clean Water, 1988 (Box 10)
      - Environment, 1988 (Box 10)
      - Housing, 1988 (Box 10)
      - Nurses, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Pollack Legislation, 1987-1988 (Box 11)
      - Pollack Record, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Public Health, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Seniors and Social Security, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Trade: Agriculture, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Talking Points, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Jackson County, 1988 (Box 11)